# **EMILY ROGALSKI**

## DATA SCIENTIST

### PROFILE

My highly technical and mathematical background along with my innate curiosity and love for learning help me find success at interpreting data and building strong machine learning models. I am a data scientist with a geophysics and research background who has a passion for analytical problem solving and experience using Python for data science and analysis.

# EXPERIENCE

#### **DATA SCIENCE FELLOW**

General Assembly | Denver, CO | 2022

- Developed skills in data gathering, data analysis, machine learning, and data visualization while completing projects in a wide variety of data science projects
- Utilized APIs and NLP to build a classification model for Reddit posts
- Cleaned and explored large datasets and presented findings to both technical and non-technical audiences

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Builders FirstSource | Denver, CO | 2019-2020

- Designed and developed a user-friendly application with intuitive navigation that both prevented human error and saved company resources.
- Provided clients with on-going support

#### MATERIALS ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN

Elementum 3D | Denver, CO | 2018-2019

- Gathered and analyzed materials properties data
- Used data to design print builds in EOS Print software

#### PROGRAM PRESENTER

Carnegie Science Center | Pittsburgh, PA | 2016-2018

• Presented science programs to audiences of up to 200

#### **RESEARCH ASSISTANT**

Boston University | Boston, MA | 2015-2017

- Modeled 3D stress change on the Cascadia fault using MATLAB and Python
- Awarded 3 separate research grants



412-770-7629



errogalski@gmail.com



Denver, CO



linkedin.com/in/emily-rogalskidata-science/

### EDUCATION

#### **BOSTON UNIVERSITY**

Bachelors in Geophysics and Planetary Sciences, Minor in Mathematics, 2012 - 2016

#### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

Certificate in Data Science, 2022

## CERTIFICATES

- Python
- Sci-Kit Learn
- Machine Learning
- Matplotlib
- Pandas
- SQL
- C++

## SKILLS

- Natural Language Processing
- APIs/ Web Scraping
- Technical Writing
- Data Analysis
- Tableau
- TensorFlow
- Git